{
  "isTheory": true,
  "openingRemarks": "Find the solution to the following equations",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "\\(7y = 6y - 13 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n7y &= 6y - 13 \\\\\n7y - 6y &= -13 \\\\\ny &= -13\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(7y\\) if \\(y=-13\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n7y &= 7(-13) \\\\\n&= -91\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(6y - 13\\) if \\(y=-13\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n6y - 13 &= 6(-13) - 13 \\\\\n&= -78 - 13 \\\\\n&= -91\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(5a + 21 = 2a \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5a + 21 &= 2a \\\\\n5a - 2a &= -21 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3a}{3} &= \\dfrac{-21}{3} \\\\\na &= -7\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(5a + 21\\) if \\(a=-7\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5a + 21 &= 5(-7) + 21 \\\\\n&= -35 + 21 \\\\\n&= -14\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(2a\\) if \\(a=-7\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n2a &= 2(-7) \\\\\n&= -14\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(k = -6k  - 35\\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nk &= -6k  - 35\\\\\nk + 6k &= -35 \\\\\n7k &= -35 \\\\\n\\dfrac{7k}{7} &= \\dfrac{-35}{7} \\\\\nk &= -5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(k\\) if \\(k=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nk &= (-5) \\\\\n&= -5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-6k - 35\\) if \\(k=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-6k - 35 &= 6(-5) - 35 \\\\\n&= 30 - 35 \\\\\n&= -5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(4x - \\dfrac{3}{8} = 3x \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4x - \\dfrac{3}{8} &= 3x \\\\\n8 \\times 4x - 8 \\times \\dfrac{3}{8} &= 8 \\times 3x \\\\\n32x - 3 &= 24x \\\\\n32x - 24x &= 3 \\\\\n8x &= 3 \\\\\n\\dfrac{8x}{8} &= \\dfrac{3}{8} \\\\\nx &= \\dfrac{3}{8}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(4x - \\dfrac{3}{8}\\) if \\(x=\\dfrac{3}{8}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4x - \\dfrac{3}{8} &= 4\\left(\\dfrac{3}{8}\\right) - \\dfrac{3}{8} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{12}{8} - \\dfrac{3}{8} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{9}{8}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(3x\\) if \\(x=\\dfrac{3}{8}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n3x &= 3\\left(\\dfrac{3}{8}\\right) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{9}{8}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(12x - 9 = 3x + 45 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n12x - 9 &= 3x + 45 \\\\\n12x - 3x &= 45 + 9 \\\\\n9x &= 54 \\\\\n\\dfrac{9x}{9} &= \\dfrac{54}{9} \\\\\nx &= 6\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(12x - 9\\) if \\(x=6\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n12x - 9 &= 12(6) - 9 \\\\\n&= 72 - 9 \\\\\n&= 63\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(3x + 45\\) if \\(x=6\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n3x + 45 &= 3(6) + 45 \\\\\n&= 18 + 45 \\\\\n&= 63\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(5n - 20 = -7n - 80 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5n - 20 &= -7n - 80 \\\\\n5n + 7n &= -80 + 20 \\\\\n12n &= -60 \\\\\n\\dfrac{12n}{12} &= \\dfrac{-60}{12} \\\\\nn &= -5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(5n - 20\\) if \\(n=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n5n - 20 &= 5(-5) - 20 \\\\\n&= -25 - 20 \\\\\n&= -45\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-7n - 80\\) if \\(n=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-7n - 80 &= -7(-5) - 80 \\\\\n&= 35 - 80 \\\\\n&= -45\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(4u + 16 = -19 - u \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4u + 16 &= -19 - u \\\\\n4u + u &= -19 - 16 \\\\\n5u &= -35 \\\\\n\\dfrac{5u}{5} &= \\dfrac{-35}{5} \\\\\nu &= -7\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(4u + 16\\) if \\(u=-7\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4u + 16 &= 4(-7) + 16 \\\\\n&= -28 + 16 \\\\\n&= -12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-19 - u\\) if \\(u=-7\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-19 - u &= -19 - (-7) \\\\\n&= -19 + 7 \\\\\n&= -12\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{5}{8}c - 4 = \\dfrac{3}{8}c + 4 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{5}{8}c - 4 &= \\dfrac{3}{8}c + 4 \\\\\n8 \\times \\dfrac{5}{8}c - 8 \\times 4 &= 8 \\times \\dfrac{3}{8}c + 8 \\times 4 \\\\\n5c - 32 &= 3c + 32 \\\\\n5c - 3c &= 32 + 32 \\\\\n2c &= 64 \\\\\n\\dfrac{2c}{2} &= \\dfrac{64}{2} \\\\\nc &= 32\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{5}{8}c - 4\\) if \\(c=32\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{5}{8}c - 4 &= \\dfrac{5}{8}(32) - 4 \\\\\n&= 20 - 4 \\\\\n&= 16\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{3}{8}c + 4\\) if \\(c=32\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{3}{8}c + 4 &= \\dfrac{3}{8}(32) + 4  \\\\\n&= 12 + 4 \\\\\n&= 16\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(6(x + 6) = 24 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n6(x + 6) &= 24 \\\\\n6x + 36 &= 24 \\\\\n6x &= 24 - 36 \\\\\n6x &= -12 \\\\\n\\dfrac{6x}{6} &= \\dfrac{-12}{6} \\\\\nx &= -2\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 24</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(6(x+6)\\) if \\(x=-2\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n6(x + 6) &= 6(-2 + 6) \\\\\n&= 6(4) \\\\\n&= 24\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(9(2p - 5) = 72 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n9(2p - 5) &= 72 \\\\\n18p - 45 &= 72 \\\\\n18p &= 72 + 45 \\\\\n18p &= 117 \\\\\n\\dfrac{18p}{18} &= \\dfrac{117}{18} \\\\\np &= 6.5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 72</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(9(2p-5)\\) if \\(p=6.5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n9(2p - 5) &= 9(2(6.5) - 5) \\\\\n&= 9(13 - 5) \\\\\n&= 9(8) \\\\\n&= 72\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    }
  ]
}
